Guide to Lopez v. Monterey County: photocopies of court case research documenting historical discrimination against Mexicans in Monterey County, California, 1855-1991
Department of Special Collections
Lopez v. Monterey County: photocopies of court case research documenting historical discrimination against Mexicans in Monterey County, California,
1855-1991
Special Collections M0944
Avila, Joaquin G., collector.
21 linear ft. (56 v. + 2 v. table of contents)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1997.
Scope and Content
The photocopies are grouped according to various subjects, the articles are also arranged chronologically, each with a cover-sheet summary of relevance to the case. Subjects covered include crime, jury selection, civil law suits, education, elections, appointments, employment, health, housing, socioeconomics, acquisition of California land grants, clubs, organizations, crime, cultural arts, events, religion, immigration, military, obituaries, accidents, etc.
Access Terms
Law--California--Monterey County--History.; Lopez v. Monterey County; Mexican Americans--Discrimination--Monterey County (Calif.); Mexican Americans--Legal status, laws, etc.--History.; Mexicans--Monterey County (Calif.)--History.; Monterey County (Calif.)--History.
Container List
- Table of Contents (Box 1, Volume 1)
- Table of Contents (Box 1, Volume 2)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits 1855-1874 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1875-1878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1879-1909 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1910-1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1953-1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Crime/Jury Selection/Civil Law Suits, 1980-1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Education, 1875-1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Education, 1875-1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Education, 1982-1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Elections/Appointments, 1855-1973 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Elections/Appointments, 1874-1875 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Elections/Appointments, 1876-1877 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Elections/Appointments, 1878-1880 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Elections/Appointments, 1882-1909 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Elections/Appointments, 1910-1938 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Elections/Appointments, 1939-1944 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Elections/Appointments, 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Elections/Appointments, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Elections/Appointments, 1947-1951 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Elections/Appointments, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Elections/Appointments, 1953-1958 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Elections/Appointments, 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Elections/Appointments, 1969-1981 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Elections/Appointments, 1982-1996 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Employment, 1869-1942 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Employment, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Employment, 1945-1947 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Employment, 1947-1952 (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Employment, 1952-1962 (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Employment, 1963-1970 (Box 10, Folder 37)
- Employment, 1970-1979 (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Employment, 1980-1991 (Box 10, Folder 39)
- Health 1968-1991 (Box 11, Folder 40)
- Housing, 1891-1947 (Box 11, Folder 41)
- Housing, 1947-1951 (Box 11, Folder 42)
- Housing, 1952-1966 (Box 11, Folder 43)
- Housing, 1967-1991 (Box 12, Folder 44)
- Socioeconomic 1872-1991 (Box 12, Folder 45)
- Acquisition of California/Land/Grants, 1875-1938 (Box 12, Folder 46)
- Acquisition of California/Land/Grants, 1938-1943 (Box 12, Folder 47)
- Acquisition of California/Land/Grants, 1944-1979 (Box 13, Folder 48)
- Clubs/Organizations; Crime 1969-1981 (Box 13, Folder 49)
- Cultural Arts/Events/Religion 1855-1952 (Box 13, Folder 50)
- Miscellaneous 1953-1989 (Box 13, Folder 51)
- Immigration 1855-1975 (Box 14, Folder 52)
- Mexico/South America 1870-1966 (Box 14, Folder 53)
- Military 1875-1969 (Box 14, Folder 54)
- Obituaries/Accidents 1870-1963 (Box 14, Folder 55)
- Other Race and Ethnicity 1871-1969 (Box 14, Folder 56)